<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LinearLayout xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
    xmlns:app="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto"
    xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    android:orientation="vertical"
    tools:context=".HelpActivity">


        <ScrollView
            android:id="@+id/scrollView2"
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="match_parent">

    <LinearLayout
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="match_parent"
        android:orientation="vertical"
        app:layout_constraintTop_toTopOf="parent"
        tools:layout_editor_absoluteX="1dp">


        <TextView
            android:id="@+id/textView3"
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="50sp"
            android:background="#00BCD4"
            android:gravity="center|left"
            android:text="   Help and Information"
            android:textColor="@color/black"
            android:textSize="20sp"
            android:textStyle="bold"
            app:layout_constraintStart_toStartOf="parent"
            app:layout_constraintTop_toTopOf="parent" />

        <TextView
            android:id="@+id/textView5"
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:layout_marginLeft="7sp"
            android:layout_marginTop="5sp"
            android:text="About"
            android:textSize="18sp"
            android:textStyle="bold" />

        <TextView
            android:id="@+id/textView6"
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:layout_marginLeft="5sp"
            android:layout_marginTop="7sp"
            android:layout_marginRight="5sp"
            android:text="Heart Disease Predictor is an application which uses Machine Learning Model to predict the chances of Heart Disease with an accuracy of 99.02%. With this it also provide you with tips to improve your health status which directly benefits your heart. \n\nHeart diseases is a term covering any disorder of the heart. Heart diseases have become a major concern to deal with as studies show that the number of deaths due to heart diseases have increased significantly over the past few decades in India, in fact it has become the leading cause of death in India. Heart disease describes a range of conditions that affect your heart. Diseases under the heart disease umbrella include blood vessel diseases, such as coronary artery disease, heart rhythm problems (arrhythmias) and heart defects you’re born with (congenital heart defects), among others. Thus preventing Heart diseases has become more than necessary. \n\nGood data-driven systems for predicting heart diseases can improve the entire research and prevention process, making sure that more people can live healthy lives. This is where Machine Learning comes into play. Machine Learning helps in predicting the Heart diseases, and the predictions made are quite accurate\n"
            android:textSize="14sp"
            app:lineHeight="18sp" />

        <TextView
            android:id="@+id/textView7"
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:layout_marginLeft="5sp"
            android:layout_marginTop="7sp"
            android:text="Dataset"
            android:textSize="18sp"
            android:textStyle="bold" />

        <TextView
            android:id="@+id/textView8"
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:layout_marginLeft="5sp"
            android:layout_marginTop="5sp"
            android:layout_marginRight="5sp"
            android:text="The dataset consists of 1030 rows with 14 features. The various features are discussed below. \n\nAge : displays the age of the individual. \nGender : displays the gender of the individual using the following format : 1 = male 0 = female. \nChest-pain type : displays the type of chest-pain experienced by the individual using the following format : 1 = typical angina 2 = atypical angina 3 = non - anginal pain 4 = asymptotic \nResting Blood Pressure : displays the resting blood pressure value of an individual in mmHg (unit) \nSerum Cholestrol : displays the serum cholestrol in mg/dl (unit) \nFasting Blood Sugar : compares the fasting blood sugar value of an individual with 120mg/dl. If fasting blood sugar > 120mg/dl then : 1 (true) else : 0 (false) \nResting ECG : 0 = normal 1 = having ST-T wave abnormality 2 = left ventricular hyperthrophy Max heart rate achieved : displays the max heart rate achieved by an individual. \nExercise induced angina : 1 = yes 0 = no \nST depression induced by exercise relative to rest : displays the value which is integer or float. \nPeak exercise ST segment : 1 = upsloping 2 = flat 3 = downsloping \nDiagnosis of heart disease : Displays whether the individual is suffering from heart disease or not : 0 = absence 1,2,3,4 = present.\n"
            app:lineHeight="20sp" />

        <TextView
            android:id="@+id/textView9"
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:layout_marginLeft="5sp"
            android:layout_marginTop="7sp"
            android:text="Why these Parameters?"
            android:textSize="18sp"
            android:textStyle="bold" />

        <TextView
            android:id="@+id/textView10"
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:layout_marginLeft="5sp"
            android:layout_marginTop="7sp"
            android:layout_marginRight="5sp"
            android:text="Angina (Chest Pain): Angina is chest pain or discomfort caused when your heart muscle doesn’t get enough oxygen- rich blood. It may feel like pressure or squeezing in your chest. The discomfort also can occur in your shoulders, arms, neck, jaw, or back. Angina pain may even feel like indigestion.
            \n\nResting Blood Pressure: Over time, high blood pressure can damage arteries that feed your heart. High blood pressure that occurs with other conditions, such as obesity, high cholesterol or diabetes, increases your risk even more.
            \n\nSerum Cholesterol: A high level of low-density lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol (the “bad” cholesterol) is most likely to narrow arteries. A high level of triglycerides, a type of blood fat related to your diet, also ups your risk of a heart attack. However, a high level of high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol (the “good” cholesterol) lowers your risk of a heart attack. \n\nFasting Blood Sugar: Not producing enough of a hormone secreted by your pancreas (insulin) or not responding to insulin properly causes your body’s blood sugar levels to rise, increasing your risk of a heart attack.
            \n\nResting ECG: For people at low risk of cardiovascular disease, the USPSTF concludes with moderate certainty that the potential harms of screening with resting or exercise ECG equal or exceed the potential benefits. For people at intermediate to high risk, current evidence is insufficient to assess the balance of benefits and harms of screening.
            \n\nMax heart rate achieved: The increase in cardiovascular risk, associated with the acceleration of heart rate, was comparable to the increase in risk observed with high blood pressure. It has been shown that an increase in heart rate by 10 beats per minute was associated with an increase in the risk of cardiac death by at least 20%, and this increase in the risk is similar to the one observed with an increase in systolic blood pressure by 10 mm Hg.
            \n\nPeak exercise ST segment: A treadmill ECG stress test is considered abnormal when there is a horizontal or down- sloping ST-segment depression ≥ 1 mm at 60–80 ms after the J point. Exercise ECGs with up-sloping ST-segment depressions are typically reported as an ‘equivocal’ test. In general, the occurrence of horizontal or down-sloping ST- segment depression at a lower workload (calculated in METs) or heart rate indicates a worse prognosis and higher likelihood of multi-vessel disease.
            \n\nST Depression:The duration of ST- segment depression is also important, as prolonged recovery after peak stress is consistent with a positive treadmill ECG stress test. Another finding that is highly indicative of significant CAD is the occurrence of ST-segment elevation > 1 mm (often suggesting transmural ischemia); these patients are frequently referred urgently for coronary angiography."
            app:lineHeight="18sp" />
    </LinearLayout>

        </ScrollView>

</LinearLayout>